Inventory of Military Department Records
Connecticut State Library
- Series 1. Old Series, 9999-9999
  - Seventh Regiment, Infantry
    - 133. Company G, 1861-1864; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box 221)
      Roster and descriptive book.
  - Eighth Regiment, Infantry
    - 134. Eighth Company, 1817-1833; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box 222)
      Record book containing extracts of General Orders, company orders, member lists, etc.
    - 135. Eighth Regiment, 1861-1871
      - Apporved discharge requests, 1866-1871; 1 inch (Box 223)
        Alphabetical by company, followed by miscellaneous.
      - Muster rolls, 1861-1865; 1.5 inches (Box 223)
        Includes some 15th Regiment.
      - Correspondence, order, clippings, a furlough pass, transportation orders, court martial report, etc., 1864-1869; 7 folders (1 inch) (Box 223)
      - 136-137. Not in use.
      - Quartermaster, 1864-1867; 1 foot (Box 224-226)
        Receipts, lists, reports and other papers pertaining to the procurement, control and distribution of supplies and equipment.
      - 139. Company B, 1861-1865; 1 volulme (.5 inch) (Box 227)
        Orderly book kept by William Gammell.
      - 140. Company D, circa 1861-1865; 1 package (3 inches) (Box 227)
        Returns, muster rolls, etc.
      - 141. Company K, 1861-1865; 2 volumes (1 inch) (Box 227)
        Record books containing roster, copies of orders and equipment assigned to each man.
  - Eleventh Regiment, Infantry
    - 142. Grenadier Company, 1794-1847; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box 228)
    - 143. First Company (Pomfret), 1833-1846; 2 volumes (1 inch) (Box 228)
      Record books.
  - Twelfth Regiment, Infantry
    - 144. Twelfth Regiment, 1863-1864; 1 bundle (.5 inch) (Box 228)
      Orders and correspondence.
  - Thirteenth Regiment, Infantry
    - 145. First Company (Woodbury), 1795-1818; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box 228)
    - 146. Company K, 1863; 1 envelope (.25 inch) (Box 228)
      Muster roll.
  - Fourteenth Regiment, Infantry
    - 147. Second Company (Berlin), 1820-1844; 2 volumes (1 inch) (Box 228)
    - 148. Sixth Company, 1823-1825; 1 volumes (.5 inch) (Box 228)
    - 149. Seventh Company, 1818-1824; 1 volumes (.5 inch) (Box 228)
    - 150. Company G, 1864-1865; 1 volume in envelope (.25 inch) (Box 228)
      Morning reports.
    - 150. Company K, 1864-1865; Shares the volume with number 150 above. (Box 228)
  - Fifteenth Regiment, Infantry
    - 151. Second Company, 1817-1826; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 229)
    - 152. Surgeon, 1864; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 229)
      Morning report book.
    - 152. Hospital Department, 1862-1865; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box 229)
      Orders and letters.
    - 154. Hospital Department, 1862-1865; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box Item 230)
      Requisitins, returns and reports.
    - 155. Hospital Department, 1862-1864; 3 volumes (3 inches) (Box Items 231-233)
      Sick and wounded register.
    - 156. Hospital Department, 1864-1865; 9 volumes (8 inches) (Box 234)
      Sick and wounded register and prescription books.
    - 157. Company G, 1865; 1 document (Box Item 235)
      Muster-out roll.
  - Eighteenth Regiment, Infantry
    - 157a. Eighteenth Regiment, Infantry, 1861-1865; 1 foot 6 inches (.5 inch) (Box 235a-c)
      Correspondence, muster rolls, ordnance reports, descriptive lists, and other records. List in first box.
      Received from C.G. Alton Means, 1950.
  - Nineteenth Regiment, Infantry
    - 158. Eighteenth Regiment, Infantry, 1838-1849; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 236)
  - Twentieth Regiment, Infantry
    - 159. First Company (Hebron), 1844-1852; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 236)
      Company book.
    - 160. Second Company (Colchester), 1838-1846; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 236)
      Gift of H.P. Buell, 1923.
  - Twenty-First Regiment, Infantry
    - 161. Veteran Association, 1870-1938; 2 volumes (1 inch) (Box 236)
      Record books of minutes, clippings, correspondence.
  - Twenty-Third Regiment, Infantry
    - 162. Third Company, 1817-1833; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 236)
  - Twenty-Fourth Regiment, Infantry
    - 163. Twenty-fourth Regiment, Infantry, 1862-1863; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box Item 237)
      Consolidated morning report book.
  - Twenty-Fifth Regiment, Infantry
    - 164. Twenty-fifth Regiment, Infantry, 1817-1845; 1 volume (1.5 inch) (Box Item 238)
      Record including muster rolls, orders, rosters and a historical sketch.
    - 165. Twenty-fifth Regiment, First Brigade, 1841-1846; 1 volume (1.5 inch) (Box 239)
      Record book of orders, minutes, etc., later used by 1st Regiment, First Brigade, 1847-1853.
    - 166. Fifth Company (East Windsor), 1825-1846; 1 volume (1.5 inch) (Box 239)
    - 167. First Flank Company, 1825-1848; 1 volume in envelope (.5 inch) (Box 239)
      Order book.
    - 168. Twenty-fifth Regiment, Infantry, 1863; 1 package (2 inches) (Box 239)
      Muster rolls and other papers.
  - Twenty-Seventh Regiment, Infantry
    - 169. Twenty-seventh Regiment, Infantry, 1862-1863; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box Item 240)
  - Twenty-Ninth, Thirtieth, and Thirty-First ("Colored") Regiments
    - 169a. Twenty-ninth, Thirtieth, and Thirty-first Colored Volunteer Regiments, 1861-1865
      - Enlistment papers, 1863-1864 (Box 1-2)
      - 29th Regiment papers, 1863-1865 (Box 2-3)
        Including muster rolls.
  - Governor's Foot Guard, First Company
    - 170. Governor's Foot Guard, First Company, 1771-1954; 12 volumes (2 feet) (Box Items 241-252)
      Record book including transcripts of laws, meeting reports passed resolutions, membership lists, correspondence, parade and celebration reports, general orders, etc.
      Nos. 1-4, 4a, 5-11.
    - 171. Company Historian, 1898-1941; 4 volumes (6 inches) (Box Items 253-256)
      Annual narratives of company activities.
    - 171. Commanding Officer, 1920-1923; 10 inches (Box 257-258)
      Alphabetical by correspondenct.
    - 173. Governor's Foot Guard, First Company, 1803-1899
      NOTE: In 1911, the Governor's Horse Guard, First Company became Troop B, Cavalry, of the National Guard. In 1917, it became part of the 101st Machine gun Battalion, 26th Division.
      - Unbound papers and miscellany, 1771-1899; 8 inches (Box 259)
        Includes correspondence, 1863-1880, muster rolls, 1803-1815, paid bills, 1897-1899, Treasurer's "skeleton reports", 1880-1893, orders, 1862-1871, deeds, leases, contracts on construction of armory, 1887-1889, receipts for new uniforms, etc., 1873, certified copy of Foot Guard Charter and other General Assembly acts, 1771 ff., and Groton celebration, 1826 and 1881.
      - Enlistment book, 1859-1907; 1 volume (.5 inch) (Box 260)
      - Roll books, circa 1895-1907; 1.5 inches (Box 260)
        Volumes A, C, and D
      - General order books, 1862-1888 (Box 260)
      - Ledger, 1862-1888; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box 260)
      - Various lists including veterans and "Home Circle", undated; 1 volume (.25 inch) (Box 265)
        Roughly alphabetical.
      - Scrapbooks, 1879-1930; Volumes 2-9, 9A and 10 (2.5 feet) (Box Items 266-275)
        Includes newspaper clippings, photographs, dinner programs amd memos, visitors' cards and other memorabilia.
      - Correspondence files, 1971; 2 volumes (Box Item 275a)
        From Major Commandant george W. Tule and Major George A. Ford concerning the 200th Anniversary Celebration, September 29-October 2, 1971.
      - Charter, 1788; 1 folder (.25 inch) (Box Item 276)
        Lithographed copy with ornamental head and Jonathan Trumbull's signature of the General Assembly resolution of 1788 creating the company. The document carries the wrong date (May 1778) and Trumbull's signature is a copy as he died in 1785. Included are notes on provenance and a reduced sized photograph.
        Photostat copies with accompanying documents are in the Catalogued Archives: 973.9 G741.
      - Record book, 1861-1879; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box Item 277)
        Includes minutes, accounts, lsits of members, etc.
      - Minutes and special order, 1911-1916; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box Item 278)
      - Enlistment papers, 1911-1919; 1 foot 8 inches (Box 279-282)
      - Scrapbook, 1911-1919; 1 volume (1 inch) (Box Item 283)
        Orders, correspondence, and memorabilia.
      - Unidentified photographs of individual company members, circa 1890-1900; 1 volume (3 inches) (Box Item 284)
    - 174-177. Not in use.
    - 178. Treasurer, 1862-1908; 3 volumes (4 inches) (Box items 261-263)
      Account books.
    - 179. Trustees, 1888-1912; 1 volume (2 inches) (Box Item 264)
      Cash book including list of subscribers to Armory building fund. See also number 173.
    - 180. Not in use.
    - 181. Equipment Committee for Uniforms and Baggage, circa 1893; 1 document
      Mounted photograph. Names on reverse.
    - 182-188. Not in use.
    - 189. Airports, Armories, and Military Reservations, 1945-1946; Photographic negatives: b&w; 8 x 10 in.
      Airports: Trumbull(5)
      Armories: Ansonia, Branford, Bridgeport, Bristol, Danbury, Danielson, Greenwich, Hartford (1945), Manchester, Meriden, Middletown, Milford, New Britain, New Haven-Goff St., New Haven-Orange St., New London, Norwalk, Norwich, Stamford, Torrington, Wallingford, Waterbury, West Hartford, West Haven, Willimantic.
      Military Reservations: Niantic (2), Stone's Ranch, East Lyme (2).
    - 190. American Expeditionary Force, 1917-1919 (Box Item 285)
      Papers, histories and other related materials of federalized Connecticut National Guard units during World War I.
    - 193. Adjutant General, 1899-1932
- Series 2. New Series, 9999-9999
  - A. Twentieth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers
    - Enlistment papers, 1862 July-August (Box 1)
    - Enlistment papers, 1863 December-1864 December (Box 2)
    - Descriptive lists, Districts 1-4, 1863 December-1864 December (Box 2)
    - Muster rolls (Box 2)
      - Companies A, B, C, D (Box 2)
      - Companies E, F, G, H, I, J (Box 3)
      - Company K (Box 4)
      - Recruits (Box 4)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 4)
    - Rolls of field & staff & companies (Box 4)
    - Muster rolls, field & staff (Box 4)
    - Muster out rolls, field & staff (Box 4)
    - Muster in rolls of officers (Box 4)
    - Returns (Box 4)
    - Quarterly return of alterations & casualties, 1864 September 30 (Box 4)
  - B. Twenty-first Regiment (Box 5)
    - Enlistment papers, Companies A, B, C (Box 5)
    - Enlistment Papers, 1862 August (Box 5)
    - Enlistment papers, 1863-1864 (Box 5)
    - Rolls of Companies A-K (Box 5)
    - Muster rolls (Box 5)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F (Box 5)
      - Companies G, H, K (Box 6)
      - Recruits (Box 6)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 6)
    - Monthly returns (Box 6)
    - Descriptive lists (Box 7)
    - Muster roll, field & staff (Box 7)
    - Returns of quarterly masters stores iwth vouchers (Box 7)
  - C. Twenty-second Regiment (Box 7)
    - Enlistment papers, petitions (Box 7)
    - Monthly returns (Box 7)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 7)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 7)
  - D. Twenty-third Regiment (Nine-month volunteers) (Box 8)
    - Letter of Governor's Aide, New Haven, 1862 October 6 (Box 8)
      Regarding enlistment of 23rd, 27th, and 28th Regiments.
    - Rolls of Companies A-K (Box 8)
    - Return of drafted men and substitutes (Box 8)
    - List of drafted men and substitutes who have deserted (Box 8)
    - Nominatin of officers, Companies A and I (Box 8)
    - Enlistment papers, petitions (Box 8)
    - Muster rolls, Companies A-K (Box 8)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 8)
    - Monthly returns (Box 8)
    - Descriptive roll, Company K (Box 8)
    - Consolidated morning report (Box 8)
    - Muster roll, field & staff (Box 8)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 8)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 8)
  - E. Twenty-fourth Regiment (Nine-month volunteers) (Box 8)
    - Muster rolls, Companies A-K (Box 8)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A-K (Box 8)
    - Muster rolls, field & staff (Box 8)
    - Enlistment papers, petitions (Box 9)
    - Monthly returns (Box 9)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 9)
    - Desciprtive lists, Companies A-K (Box 9)
    - Drafted men and substitutes absent without leave (Box 9)
  - F. Twenty-fifth Regiment (Box 9)
    - Memo from F. Atwood to the Adjutant General, Hartford, 1897 October 14 (Box 9)
      Regarding Civil War souvenir.
    - Battle report from Lt. Col. M.C. Weld, "Before Port Hudson", 1863 June 18 (Box 9)
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 9)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 9)
    - Field & staff muster rolls, descriptive lists, muster out rolls (Box 9)
    - Muster out rolls, detatchments (Box 9)
    - Enlistment papers, petitions, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 9)
    - Rolls of Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, 2 sets (Box 9)
    - Descriptive lists, Companies A, B, D, F, G, H, I (Box 10)
    - Returns (Box 10)
    - Muster in rolls of officers (Box 10)
    - Morning reports, Consolidated morning reports (Box 10)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 10)
  - G. Twenty-sixth Regiment (Box 10)
    - Enlistment papers, petitions, Companies A, B, D, F, G, H, I, K (Box 10)
    - Rolls of Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 10)
    - Muster in rolls, Companies A, B, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 10)
    - Field & staff descriptive list, muster rolls (Box 10)
    - Returns (Box 10)
    - Descriptive lists, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 10)
    - Morning report (Box 10)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 10)
  - H. Eighteenth Regiment (Box 11)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 11)
    - Muster in rolls of officers (Box 11)
    - Descriptive lists, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I (Box 11)
    - Descriptive lists of one recruit (Box 12)
    - Field & staff (Box 12)
      - Muster rolls (Box 12)
      - Muster rolls, Hospital (Box 12)
      - Descriptive list (Box 12)
      - Muster out roll (Box 12)
    - Monthly returns (Box 12)
    - Circular in regard to evidence on file relating to the death of Sgt. Ichabod Davis (Box 12)
    - Muster rolls (Box 12)
      - Companies A, B, C (Box 12)
      - Companies D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 13)
      - Recurits (Box 13)
    - Muster out rolls, officers (Box 14)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 14)
    - Muster out rolls, individual soldiers (Box 14)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 14)
  - I. Miscellaneous War Papers (Box 14)
    - Amended service records pf Civil War veterans (Box 14)
    - Records of Revolutionary War up to 1812 (Box 14)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 14)
      - U.S. Army (including 31st Colored) & Navy (Box 14)
      - Other states (Box 14)
      - Connecticut Volunteers, First, Third, Fifth, Sixth, Seventh, Ninth, tenth, Eleventh, Twelfth, and Thirteenth Regiments (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous letters regarding veterans, etc. (Box 15)
    - Certificates for substitutes for enlistment (Box 15)
      - Hartford, Conn., Number 1-54, 1864 December 1-15 (Box 15)
      - Hartford, Conn., Number 1-233, 1864 October-1865 April (Box 15)
    - Desertions, corrected or retracted Act of Congress, March 2, 1889, Ives-Wright (Box 15)
  - J. First Connecticut Cavalry (Box 16)
    When first formed, this unit was called a Battalion. Later it was called a Regiment. Also, at some point parts of this Regiment were transfered to the Second New York Cavalry.
    - Muster rolls (Box 16)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F (Box 16)
      - Companies G, H, K, L, M (Box 17)
      - Field & staff (Box 17)
      - Recruits (Box 17)
      - of a detachment, 1865-1866 (Box 17)
      - Company D, 1st Squadron, Connecticut 1st Cavalry Volunteers (Box 17)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 17)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, L, M (Box 17)
      - Field & staff (Box 17)
    - Enlistment rolls, Companies A, B, C, D (Box 17)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 17)
      - Companies G, H, I, K (Box 18)
      - Capt. Upson's Company (Box 18)
    - Descriptive lists from Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 18)
      - 1863 December-1864 March (Box 18)
      - 1865 April-October (Box 18)
      - 1864 November-1865 (Box 19)
      - Veterans (Box 19)
    - Returns (Box 19)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments (i.e. soldiers), Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, L, M and unassigned (Box 19)
    - Discharge papers, non-commissioned officers (Box 20)
    - Officers and non-commissioned officers discharged for promotion (Box 20)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous papers, First Connecticut Cavalry Volunteers (Box 20)
      - Enlistment paper, John Williams (Box 20)
      - Military records of certain soldiers, 1878 July 29 (Box 20)
      - War Department correspondence, 1878 October (Box 20)
        List of 58 ,names of First Squadron Connecticut Cavalry Volunteers consolidated with Second New York Cavalry Volunteers.
      - War Department correspondence, 1878 (Box 20)
        Amending official records for certain soldiers.
    - Miscellaneous papers, First Squadron, Connecticut Cavalry Volunteers (Box 20)
      Note: This was part of a multi-state regiment, not First Connecticut Volunteer Cavalry.
      - Enlistment rolls (Box 20)
      - Re-enlisted veterans (Box 20)
      - Returns (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous papers, Second Regiment New York Volunteers (Box 21)
      - Muster rolls (Box 21)
      - Descriptive lists (Box 21)
      - Returns (Box 21)
      - Muster out rolls (Box 21)
  - K. First Connecticut Volunteer Heavy Artillery (Box 20)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 20)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 21)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 22)
    - Enlistment papers & election of officers (Box 22)
    - Muster in rolls, enlistment rolls, rolls of recruits (Box 22)
    - Muster in rolls & returns, veterans (Box 22)
    - Muster rolls
      - Companies A, B, C, D (Box 23)
      - Companies E, F, G, I (Box 24)
      - Companies I, K, L, Recruits (Box 25)
    - Descriptive lists (Box 25)
    - Descriptive lists (Box 26)
    - Descriptive lists, veterans (Box 26)
    - Monthly returns (Box 26)
    - Lists of soldiers eligible for first monthly bounty, Companies A, B, C, E, I. 2 unidentified companies (Box 27)
    - List of married men (Box 27)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, I, K, L, M, and several unidentified (Box 27)
    - Muster out rolls, detachments (Box 27)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 27)
    - Field & staff (including band, surgeon, hospital) (Box 27)
      - Muster rolls (Box 27)
      - Bounty lists (Box 27)
      - Muster out rolls (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous documents (Box 27)
      Copy of habeus corpus for Elias Babcock, Jr.
    - Officers
      - Muster in rolls (Box 28)
      - Muster out papers (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 28)
      - Returns of officers (Box 28)
      - Letters of acceptance, resignation, and volunteering (Box 28)
  - L. First Connecticut Light Battery (Box 28)
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 28)
    - Descriptive lists (Box 28)
    - Muster rolls (Box 28)
    - Monthly returns (Box 28)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 28)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 28)
    - Enlistment roll (Box 29)
    - Discharge papers (Box 29)
  - M. First Regiment Connecticut Volunteer Infantry (three month) (Box 29)
    - Muster out rolls, Companies B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 29)
    - Roll of infantry (Enlistment rolls), Companies B, C, D, E, plus two roll unidentified as to company or regiment (Box 29)
    - Monthly bounty lists (Box 29)
      - 1st monthly bounty, Companies B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 29)
      - 2nd monthly bounty, Companies B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 29)
      - 3rd monthly bounty, Companies B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 29)
    - Muster rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 29)
    - Returns of officers (elections), Companies A, B, C, D, F, G (Box 29)
    - Muster in rolls, Pvt. C. Walters, Muster out roll of Pvt. and Lt. C. Walters (Box 29)
  - N. Second Regiment (Box 29)
    - Lists of monthly bounty payments, 1st, 2nd, and 3rd months (Box 29)
      Lists by company by mostly identified only by Captain's name.
      Note: the company identifications for the first three regiments of Connecticut Volunteers (three months) are confusing. Some companies are identified as "Rifle", some as "Infantry". Furthermore companies were given one identification, A, B, C, etc. by the State when the regiment was formed, but this designation was changed when the regiment was mustered into the U.S. forces. See the following volume to straighten this out, Record of Connecticut Men in the War of the Rebellion, 1861-1865, Part I. Many documents are identified only by the Captain's name.
    - Muster rolls
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F (Box 33)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F (Box 33)
      - Recruits (Box 33)
    - Muster out rolls
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, L, M (Box 35)
      - Detachments (Box 35)
      - Detachments (Box 36)
      - Field & staff (Box 36)
      - Officers (Box 36)
    - Descriptive rolls (Box 36)
      - Recruits, Districts 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 36)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 36)
      - Transfers from Companies I, K, L, M to other Companies (Box 37)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 36)
  - O. Not in use.
  - P. Second Connecticut Light Battery (Box 36)
    - Muster rolls (Box 36)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 36)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 36)
    - Descriptive rolls (Box 36)
    - Returns (Box 36)
    - Reports on strength of Second Connecticut Light Battery in Louisiana (Box 36)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 36)
  - Q. Third Connecticut Light Battery (Box 38)
    - Descriptive rolls (Box 38)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 38)
    - Muster rolls (Box 38)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 38)
    - Descriptive rolls, Members of Third Connecticut Battery transferred to First Connecticut Artillery (Box 38)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 38)
  - R. Harlan's Connecticut Volunteer Band, Thrid Brigade Connecticut Volunteer Band, Thrid Brigate Siege Artillery (Box 38)
    - Muster rolls (Box 38)
    - Enlistment papers (Box 38)
    - Returns (Box 38)
  - S. Not in use.
  - T. Fifth Connecticut Volunteer Infantry (Box 38)
    - Colonel Sam Colt's Regiment, disbanded (Box 38)
      Muster rolls, Return of officers.
    - Enlistment papers, new recruits, 1862-1864 (Box 38)
    - Muster rolls (Box 38)
      - Recruits (Box 38)
      - Company A (Box 38)
      - Companies B, C, D, E, F (Box 40)
    - Enlistment papers, veterans re-enlisting from Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H (Box 40)
    - Muster rolls, Companies G, H, I, K, Field & staff (including Band & Hospital) (Box 41)
    - Muster in rolls (Box 41)
      - Officers (Box 41)
      - Non-commissioned officers, veterans (Box 41)
    - Muster out rolls (Box 42)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 42)
      - Officers & staff, Band, Doctor (Box 42)
      - Detachments (Box 42)
    - Monthly returns (including quarterly returns of deceased) (Box 42)
    - Descriptive rolls (Box 42)
      - Band, List of deserters (Box 42)
      - Recruits, Districts, 1, 2, 3, 4 (Box 42)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K, Field & staff (Box 42)
    - Pay & bounty rolls, Companies A, B, C, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 42)
    - Enlistment rolls & returns of officers, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 42)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 42)
      - Returns of officers (rolls, elections) (Box 42)
      - Offers of service (petition) (Box 42)
  - U. Fourteenth Connecticut Volunteers
    - Muster in rolls, officers (Box 43)
    - Enlistment papers
      - Non-commissioned officers (Box 44)
      - Non-commissioned officers (Box 44)
      - Thirty two who deserted en route to Regiment (Box 44)
      - Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, K (Box 44)
    - Monthly returns (Box 44)
    - Muster & descriptive rolls, Companies A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, K (Box 44)
    - Printed list of members of Fourteenth Regiment Connecticut Volunteers (with cover letter) (Box 44)
    - Original discharge papers (Box 44)